571.244.8331

office@web4u2.website

www.web4u2.website

Summary

Over 25 years experience managing customer experience and employees in the hotel and restaurant industry. The last year has been focused on expanding upon previous web design experience as well as hotel and restaurant customer management experience to building and designing web projects.

Experience

Web Design and Development Experience

Bootstrap Teacher at NOVA Workforce Division

07/2016 to Present

Lead teacher and creator of Building Fluid Sites with Bootstrap Shortcuts class. The course offers students hands on technical experience with multiple exercises building up to a full website.

Teacher's Assistant NOVA Web Design Certificate Program

09/2014 to Present

Lead Teacher's Assistant for NOVA's Web Design Certificate Program. Providing technical hands-on support and education for up to 15 adult students learning web design classes twice a week.

Consultant for MachMedia and their client Market Voice Magazine

09/2015 to 12/2015

Consultant for Mach Media fixing existing site issues, creating blocks and navigation, styling with CSS as well as creating new pages including wireframes. Worked with Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Drupal including some backend PHP fixes and basic Unix command line.

Virginia Grand Military Band (VGMB) Site Re-design

12/2014 to 8/2015

Web Designer for complete web site re-design for the VGMB. Responsible for gathering requirements as well as developing wireframes, documenting the design approach for sponsor approval while utilizing existing website as a guide. Performing an absolute design re-write to enhance and better market the band's performances and performers. Technologies include CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap, Adobe Photoshop, and Dreamweaver.

Reunion Project 09/2014 to Present

Lead Web Designer for 50th Year High School Reunion project. Tasked with building a website to capture up to 200 names, addresses, and special memories. Data capture and storage uses Google web docs to complete source data for a 50th Year High School Reunion Yearbook. Leveraging Adobe Photoshop to enhance photographs as well as isolate each student for before and after photos.

Yacht Charter Business, Croatia

2002-2014

Half-owner of a family run Yacht Carter business in Croatia serving licensed vacationing customers. Supported operations in summer. Designed, developed, and maintained flash-based website using Dreamweaver.

Hotel & Restaurant Management & Customer Service Experience

Landhotel Postgut, Tweng, Austria

2013-2014

Front Desk Manager responsible for checking in guests for a four star hotel, booking rooms, using hotel specific management/booking software, author and creator of daily activities for guests including an inspirational saying to welcome the day in German and English.

Hotel Tauernpasshoehe, Obertauern, Austria

1995-2013

Assistant Hotel Manager for a family run ski hotel with 25 rooms. Responsible for hotel operations, managing 6 employees, and keeping customers satisfied. Performed IT/Systems integration and technical engineering including website development, system support, WiFi/Internet configuration. Performed analysis, design, development and deployment of hotel website using Dreamweaver.

Education

Northern Virginia Community College Arlington, VA

Web Design Certificate 2014

Northern Virginia Community College Woodbridge, VA

Web Developer Certificate 2016

Hotel Restaurant Management Franchise License Salzburg, Austria

3/2010 to 6/2010

Holds a Hotel Restaurant Management Franchise License after completing an extensive exam and passing with the highest honors. This is a license to own and operate a hotel, bar or restaurant including proper health and safety requirements for food and drink storage, handling and processing. Proper financial management skills were required to complete the license to ensure the ability to run a profitable business with understanding of calculation for buying, renting, food purchase, room management, to personnel management.

Hotel & Restaurant Management School Villach, Austria

9/1989 to 6/1995

Completed an advanced degree in Hotel and Restaurant Management

Technical Skills

JavaScript, jQuery, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, WordPress, Drupal, HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, basic Unix command line, all devices using Windows to Apple.

NOVA Web Design Certificate classes 2014

Introduction to Web Page Design (HTML), Mobile Layout with CSS, Effective Web Design with Dreamweaver, Photoshop for the Web, Building Websites with Free Content Management Systems, HTML5 and CSS3 for Web Frontiers.

NOVA Web Developer Certificate classes 2015/2016

Basic Web Management, JavaScript Basics, JavaScript Advanced, jQuery and JavaScript

Trainings 2015

JSON, XML, PHP, Drupal, AngularJS and D3 JS-Data-Visualization

Personal Traits

A great team player able to drive employees during high stress situations; personable, customer-focused; easily picks up new skills; eager to learn; great with calculations, and an excellent memory for customer requests.